Rahul Srinivasan (1) Featured

ITIL,IT Analyst,Seeking roles in IT Project Management,Application Development,Requirement Gathering,Software Development,Application Programming,Base SAS,SAS Macros,SQL,Unix Shell Scripting,Linux



Current Designation: Senior Associate Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Cognizant Technologies Solutions Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Chennai Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E.
Pref. Location: Chennai [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: IT Analyst, Software Developer, IT Project Management, Application Development, Requirement

Gathering, Software Development, Application Programming, Base SAS, SAS Macros, SQL, Unix Shell Scripting, Linux

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 12-Jan-21 Last Modified: 5-Jan-21

Summary

SAS Certified Advanced Programmer with 6.5 years experience in Unix/Linux based systems, having sound working knowledge of BASE SAS Programming, SAS Macros, Proc SQL and UNIX shell scripting.

Proven leadership credentials, having successfully lead a team of 5 members for various implementations and migrations over the past two years.

ITIL certified professional with a thorough understanding of production support environment.

Excellent Analytical, Technical and Communication skills.

Attitude & Ability to coordinate as a good team player and to work as self-motivated individual.

Work Experience

Cognizant Technologies Solutions as Senior Associate

Nov 2018 to Till Date

SAS developer /Data analyst

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES LIMITED as IT Analyst - Application Programming Oct 2011 to Nov 2018

Projects:

1) Title : Common Data Area (CDA) Period : July 2012 - Present

Client Name: Citigroup Inc., North America Information Technology

Position: Developer. Project description:

CDA application is primarily involved in the collection of data from various sources, and transforming them into SAS datasets, thereby acting as a data-warehouse. CDA primarily serves to analyze the activities taking place with Citi retail cards in the North American geography. CDA comes under a bigger umbrella of Citi BI applications, which aids and guides the higher management for their DSS (Decision Support Systems) activities. CDA application is also responsible for ensuring that the integrity of the datasets are protected, and ensures that only the valid users have access to the data, by setting up the proper ACL ?s (Access Control List).In order to accomplish the aforementioned activities in a periodic and in an automated manner, the autosys scheduler is made use of.

2) Title: RAPID RESPONCE TEAM(RRT)

Period: July 2012 - Present

Client Name: Citigroup Inc., North America Information Technology

Position: Developer. Project description:

RRT application is a downstream of CDA and unlike CDA users, who are SAS users, the RRT users are high level users and all the reports generated here are end reports. RRT uses CDA datasets and external files and create report using them, which are delivered to users by mail or other forms of transmissions like SFTP, NDM, etc. There are many SLA critical reports in RRT.

3)Title: DSM? DATA SERVICES MANAGEMENT (VISUALIZATION)

Period: July 2012 - Present

Client Name: Citigroup Inc., North America Information Technology

Position: Developer

Project:

DSM or otherwise called visualization is again a downstream of CDA. Again the DSM users are high level users, who are not well versed with SAS. In DSM, CDA SAS data is used and files are created in the CSV format and the same are loaded into COGNOS cubes.

4)Title: Macy?s Partner addition

Period: September 2015

Client Name: Citigroup Inc., North America Information Technology

Position: Technical Lead Project description:

This project involved in addition of Macy's to the list of existing partners. This project lead to an addition of 500+ SAS jobs in the production environment .I Performed end to end pre- migration and post migration tasks by leading a team of 3 members and brought down the incident count by suggesting various code fixes.

5)Title: SAS GRID Migration Period : March 2016

Client Name: Citigroup Inc., North America Information Technology

Position : Technical Lead Project description:

This project involved in migration of three production servers from Unix based environment to an integrated Linux based grid environment. Successfully lead a team of 5 members and accomplished the following

- Transfer of 60TB of production data and migration of 7000+ autosys jobs from UNIX to Linux environment.
- 2) Worked with multiple vendors to address the Unix/Linux compatibility issues.
- 3) Performed end to end application and connectivity (NDM, FTP, and Database) checkouts.
- 4) Ensured the integrity of the datasets created by the production batch.
- 5) Liaised with various stakeholders (internal, external and third party) and handled user communications.
- 6) Analyzed and resolved the data issues reported by the business users

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from SRM Easwari Engineering College, Chennai in 2011

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

SAS CERTIFIED ADVANCED PROGRAMMER

SAS CERTIFIED BASE PROGRAMMER

ITIL FOUNDATION

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
SQL,Autosys			
BASE SAS,Unix ,SAS Macros			
Unix shell scripting			

Languages Known

1/22/2021	https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname = 67f600ab688c70f627022952a0fa08775a0e095743125c155110465f5b00ab688c70f627022952a0fa08775a0e095743125c155110465f5b00ab688c70f627022952a0fa08775a0e095743125c155110465f5b00ab688c70f627022952a0fa08775a0e095743125c155110465f5b00ab688c70f627022952a0fa08775a0e095743125c155110465f5b00ab688c70f627022952a0fa08775a0e095743125c155110465f5b00ab688c70f627022952a0fa08775a0e095743125c155110465f5b00ab688c70f627022952a0fa08775a0e095743125c155110465f5b00ab688c70f627022952a0fa08775a0e095743125c155110465f5b00ab688c70f627022952a0fa08775a0e095743125c155110465f5b00ab688c70f627022952a0fa08775a0e095743125c155110465f5b00ab688c70f627022952a0fa08775a0e095743125c155110465f5b00ab688c70f627022952a0fa08775a0e095743125c155110465f5b00ab688c70f627022952a0fa08765a0e0095743125c155110465f5b00ab68666666666666666666666666666666666
1	

English		
Tamil		

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time